A Finding Aid to the Ben Shahn Papers, 1879-1990, bulk 1933-1970, in the Archives of American Art AAA.shahben
Archives of American Art
- Letters, 1929-1990; Series 2; 14.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-25, 35, OVs 36-38
  - United Automobile Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1963-1968 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - United Automobile Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Exhibition, circa 1946-circa 1947 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - United Automobile Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, Exhibition, circa 1940s-1964 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - United Church Board for Homeland Ministries, 1962-1967 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - United Jewish Appeal, circa 1962-1968 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF), 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - U. S. Camera, 1935-1946 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - U. S. Dept. of Agriculture, Farm Security Administration, 1935-1936; 3 Folders (Box 23, Folder 42-44)
    (includes notes and doodles by Shahn)
  - U. S. Dept. of Agriculture, Farm Security Administration, 1937-1939; 3 Folders (Box 23, Folder 45-47)
  - U. S. Dept. of the Treasury, Section of Fine Arts and War Finance Division, 1933-1944 (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - U. S. Federal Works Agency, Public Buildings Administration, and Works Project Administration, 1936-1943 (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - U. S. General Services Administration, 1953-1962, 1972, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - U. S. Information Agency, 1955-1968 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    (includes letter from Shahn regarding his painting removed from a traveling exhibition)
  - U. S. National Commission for UNESCO, Reports and Minutes of Meetings, 1948-1950 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - U. S. National Commission for UNESCO, Visual Arts Panel, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - U. S. Office for Emergency Management, 1942-1945 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - U. S. Office of War Information, 1942-1943; 2 Folders (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - University of Arkansas, 1951-1953 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - University of Buffalo, 1951-1952 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - University of California, Various Locations, 1959-1968 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago, 1956-1967, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - University of Colorado, 1949-1964 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - University of Illinois, 1949-1967, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - University of Maryland, 1962-1968, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - University of Michigan, 1953-1969 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - University of Minnesota, 1951-1966, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - University of New Mexico, 1963-1980 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - University of North Carolina, 1958-1965 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - University of Oregon, 1957-1964, 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1956-1968, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - University of Texas, 1944-1963, 1973-1979 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1949-1968, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - U, Miscellaneous: Ud - United States Festival, 1945-1969 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - U, Miscellaneous: United States Government Departments, 1937-1967 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - U, Miscellaneous: United Steel - University of Cincinatti, 1949-1969 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - U, Miscellaneous: University of Connecticut - University of Missouri, 1953-1968 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - U, Miscellaneous: University of Nebraska - Ut, 1945-1969 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - U, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1970-1986 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - V. Foscato, Inc., 1956-1967 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Valentin, Curt, 1947-1954 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Vassar College, circa 1948-1964, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Veblen College, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Viking Press Inc., 1953-1964, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Vintage Books, Inc., 1956-1960 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1956-1968 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Vogue, 1947-1958 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Volpi, Carla Lonzi and Marisa, circa 1939-1964 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - V, Miscellaneous, V. - Va, 1954-1968 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - V, Miscellaneous, Ve - Vo, 1949-1968 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - V, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1970-1990 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - V, First Names Only, circa 1960s (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - WCBS-TV, 1954, 1962-1968 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    see Series 10: Interview Transcripts for texts of interviews
  - WGBH -FM, 1957-1961 (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - WQED, Channel 13, 1956-1965 (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Wada, Makato, circa 1957-1961 (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1946-1964 (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - War/Peace Report, circa 1955-1969 (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - Washeba, John, circa 1957-circa 1962 (Box 24, Folder 43)
    (includes 1962 Christmas card to Washeba from the Shahns)
  - Washington University, St. Louis, 1947-1961 (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - Weber, Palmer, 1948-1953, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1958-1961 (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - Westheimer, Charles, 1971-1983 (Box 24, Folder 47)
  - Wheeler, Monroe, circa 1953-1967 (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - White House, 1964-1968 (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - Whiting, Ccile, 1984-1988 (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1935-1951 (Box 24, Folder 51)
    (includes 1948 letter from Shahn)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1952-1968 (Box 24, Folder 52)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1974-1985 (Box 24, Folder 53)
  - Who's Who, Various Publications, 1941-1967 (Box 24, Folder 54)
  - Willet Stained Glass Studios, 1966-1968, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 55)
  - Williams, Jonathan ( Jargon), 1954-1964 (Box 24, Folder 56)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 57)
  - Wilmington Society of the Fine Arts, 1955-1960 (Box 24, Folder 58)
  - Wittenberg, Philip and Ruth, circa 1961-1966 (Box 24, Folder 59)
  - Wolff, Eleanor L., 1950-1958 (Box 24, Folder 60)
  - Wolff, Kurt, see: Pantheon Books (Box 24)
  - Wolff, Rudi, circa 1957-1968 (Box 24, Folder 61)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1962-1966 (Box 24, Folder 62)
  - Woodstock Artists Association, 1943-1953 (Box 24, Folder 63)
  - Worcester Art Museum, circa 1945-1955 (Box 24, Folder 64)
  - World Law Fund, 1965, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 65)
  - W, Miscellaneous: W., 1953-1967 (Box 24, Folder 66)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wad - Wal, 1949-1969 (Box 24, Folder 67)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wan - Way, 1948-1969 (Box 24, Folder 68)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wee - Wen, 1951-1968 (Box 24, Folder 69)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wer - Whe, 1950-1968 (Box 24, Folder 70)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Whi - Wilc, 1951-1968 (Box 24, Folder 71)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Will - Wilt, 1952-1968 (Box 24, Folder 72)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Win - Wl, 1948-1967 (Box 24, Folder 73)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wol - Woo, 1950-1968 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wor - Wy, 1950-1968 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - W, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1969-1988 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - W, First Names Only, circa 1961-1965 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Yale University, 1949-1966 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Yale University, 1967-1968, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Yamada Art Gallery (Ayako and Tetsuo Yamada), 1960-1970 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    (includes Christmas card from the Yamadas with original artwork)
  - Yivo Institute for Jewish Research, 1962-1963 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Yochelson, Kathryn M., 1955-1958 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Yoshi (name illegible), 1957-1963 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Y, Miscellaneous, 1945-1969 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Y, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1970-1988 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Zetzel, Louis, circa 1957-1964 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Z, Miscellaneous, 1944-1969 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Z, Miscellaneous, Posthumous, 1970-1982 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Condolence Telegrams, 1969 March (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Condolence Letters, A, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Condolence Letters, B, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Condolence Letters, C, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Condolence Letters, D, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Condolence Letters, E, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Condolence Letters, F, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Condolence Letters, G, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Condolence Letters, H-J, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Condolence Letters, K, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Condolence Letters, L, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Condolence Letters, M, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Condolence Letters, N-P, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Condolence Letters, R, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Condolence Letters, S, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Condolence Letters, T-V, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Condolence Letters, W-Z, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Letters Unsigned or with Illegible Signatures, circa 1940s-circa 1960s (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Letters Unsigned or with Illegible Signatures, 1938-1959 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Letters Unsigned or with Illegible Signatures, 1961-1969 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Letters Unsigned or with Illegible Signatures, Posthumous, 1969-1986 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Letters with Multiple Signatures, circa 1960s (Box 25, Folder 37)
    (includes original ink drawing)
  - Empty Envelopes, 1957-1967 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Unidentified Notes and Fragments, circa 1940s-circa 1960s (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Oversized Material from L, Miscellaneous: Lor - Loz, 1945-1968 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 18, F3
  - Oversized Material from Museum of Modern Art, 1948-1950 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 18, F52
  - Oversized Material from N, Miscellaneous: Nac-Nath, 1947-1969 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 19, F46
  - Oversized Material from Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, circa 1950s (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 20, F5-6
  - Oversized Material from Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 20, F7-8
  - Oversized Material from Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, 1952-1962 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 20, F9
  - Oversized Material from Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, 1963-1966 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 20, F11
  - Oversized Material from Osborn, Elodie and Robert Chelsey, 1969-1972 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 20, F13
  - Oversized Material from Riker's Island Prison Mural, Photos and Reproductions, circa 1935 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 21, F16
  - Oversized Material from Roston, Arnold, circa 1963-1968, 1980 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 21, F29
  - Oversized Material from Shahn, Abigail, circa 1940s-1968 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 21, F64
  - Oversized Material from Shahn, Ben and Bernarda Bryson, circa 1962-1969 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 21, F65
  - Oversized Material from Stedelijk Museum, 1953-1967, 1978 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 22, F38
  - Oversized Material from Letters Unsigned or with Illegible Signatures, circa 1940s-circa 1960s (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 25, F33
  - Oversized Material from Nakashima, George and Marion, circa 1954-1969, 1984 (Box OV 36)
    oversized material scanned with Box 19, F17
  - Oversized Material from V. Foscato, Inc., 1956-1967 (Box OV 36)
    oversized material scanned with Box 24, F24
  - Oversized Material from S, Miscellaneous: Se, 1953-1968 (Box OV 38)
    oversized material scanned with Box 22, F51
- Project Files, 1933-1975; Series 3; 1.03 Linear feet Boxes 25-26; OVs 36-37
  Project files document approximately twenty-one of Shahn's commissions. Some projects are more fully documented than others with files containing correspondence tracing the evolution and execution of a project, including some letters from Shahn, in addition to proposals, contracts, scattered notes and sketches, blueprints, specifications, financial and printed material, and photographs. However, some projects listed here were ultimately never executed or are represented by only a few items such as receipts, specifications, and photographs. The series includes files for some of Shahn's most important mural commissions such as those for the Jersey Homesteads community center, the Bronx Central Post Office, and the Social Security building in Washington D.C.
  Files documenting the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial in Roosevelt, New Jersey, include contact prints of the memorial's designer, Shahn's son Jonathan Shahn, and his portrait bust of Roosevelt, in addition to a photograph of Ben Shahn at the dedication ceremony for the memorial.
  Files are arranged chronologically. This bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of negatives and some oversized blueprints and plans.
  - Rockefeller Center Mural, New York, Specifications, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    (specifications for metal furring, lathing and plastering only)
  - "Greenbelt" Community, Greenbelt MD, Proposed Film by Shahn and Walker Evans, 1936 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Jersey Homesteads Community Center Fresco Mural, Roosevelt NJ (Box 25)
    - General, circa 1936-1941; 2 Folders (Box 25, Folder 42-43)
    - Photos of Artists and Artwork, circa 1936-1941 (Box 25, Folder 44)
      (including photos of Lenore Thomas working on sculpture and Otto Wester working on aluminum bas relief door panels)
    - Photos of Construction, circa 1936-1941 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Negatives of Construction, circa 1936-1941 (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Bronx Central Annex Post Office Murals, NY, 1938; 2 Folders (Box 25, Folder 47-48)
  - Bronx Central Annex Post Office Murals, NY, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - St. Louis Post Office Mural, MO, Prospectus, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - Green Hills, Wisconsin, Mural Proposal, circa 1940s (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - Jamaica Post Office Tempera Panel, Long Island, NY, 1940-1941; 2 Folders (Box 25, Folder 52-53)
    oversized material housed in OV 37
  - Social Security Building Mural, Washington DC, 1940-1941 (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - Social Security Building Mural, Washington DC, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 55)
  - Social Security Building Mural, Washington DC, 1941-1942 (Box 25, Folder 56)
  - William E. Grady Vocational High School Mosaic Mural, Brooklyn, NY, 1955-1957 (Box 25, Folder 57)
  - St. John's Abbey Church, Collegeville, MN, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 58)
  - "Him" by E. E. Cummings, Set Design, Spoleto, Italy, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 59)
  - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial, Roosevelt, NJ (Box 26)
    - General, circa 1961 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - General, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - General, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Receipts, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material, circa 1961-1962 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - S. S. Shalom Mosaic Murals, 1962-1969 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Temple Beth Zion Window, Buffalo, NY, 1964-1967 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - LeMoyne College Library Mural, Memphis, TN, 1961-1964 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - "Play with a Tiger" by Doris Lessing, Set Design, Renata Theatre, New York, NY, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    oversized material housed in OV 36-not scanned
  - Spivak Residence Mosaic Murals, Far Hills, NJ, 1965-1967 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - John F. Kennedy Center for Research on Education and Human Development, George Peabody College for Teachers, Mural, Nashville, TN, 1965-1970; 2 Folders (Box 26, Folder 12-13)
  - Demonstration School Mural, State University of New York, Buffalo, New York, 1966-1967 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Huntington Beard Crouse Building Outdoor Mosaic Mural, Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Shahn Grave Monument Designed by Bernarda Bryson Shahn, 1970-1975 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Plans for Miscellaneous Projects, circa 1930s-1958 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    oversized material housed in OV 39
  - Oversized Material from Jersey Homesteads Community Center Fresco Mural, Roosevelt NJ, General, circa 1936-1941 (Box OV 36)
    oversized material scanned with Box 25, F42
  - Oversized Material from Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial, Roosevelt, NJ, General, 1962 (Box OV 36)
    oversized material scanned with Box 26, F2
  - Oversized Material, "Play with a Tiger" by Doris Lessing, Set Design, Renata Theatre, New York, NY, 1964 (Box OV 36)
    oversized material from Box 26, F10
    not scanned
  - Oversized Material from Spivak Residence Mosaic Murals, Far Hills, NJ, 1965-1967 (Box OV 36)
    oversized material scanned with Box 26, F11
  - Oversized Material from Demonstration School Mural, State University of New York, Buffalo, New York, 1966-1967 (Box OV 36)
    oversized material scanned with Box 26, F14
  - Oversized Material from Shahn Grave Monument Designed by Bernarda Shahn, 1970-1975 (Box OV 36)
    oversized material scanned with Box 26, F16
  - Oversized Material from Jamaica Post Office Tempera Panel, Long Island, NY, 1940-1941 (Box OV 37)
    oversized material scanned with Box 25, F52
  - Oversized Material from Social Security Building Mural, Washington DC, 1940-1941 (Box OV 37)
    oversized material scanned with Box 25, F54
  - Oversized Material from St. John's Abbey Church, Collegeville, MN, 1960-1961 (Box OV 37)
    oversized material scanned with Box 25, F58
  - Oversized Material from S. S. Shalom Mosaic Murals, 1962-1969 (Box OV 37)
    oversized material scanned with Box 26, F7
  - Oversized Material from Temple Beth Zion Window, Buffalo, NY, 1964-1967 (Box OV 37)
    oversized material scanned with Box 26, F8
  - Oversized Material from J.F.K. Center for Research on Education and Human Development, George Peabody College for Teachers, Mural, Nashville, TN, 1965-1970 (Box OV 37)
    oversized material scanned with Box 26, F12
  - Plans for Miscellaneous Projects, circa 1930s-1958 (Box OV 39)
    oversized material scanned from Box 26, F17
- Financial and Legal Records, 1934-1988; Series 4; 1.62 Linear feet Boxes 26-27, 35
  Shahn's art-related financial material includes consignment records, loan agreements, and royalty statements, in addition to receipts for artwork sold, receipts for publication of artwork, and receipts for honoraria and other payments. Much of the series consists of routine transactions not necessarily related to Shahn's work including bank records, miscellaneous receipts, records of medical expenses, and insurance records.
  Three folders at the end of the series contain legal documents and records relating to a police report of a case in which Shahn had assisted by drawing a sketch of a criminal suspect.
  The series is partially scanned. Routine and personal financial records and tax records have not been scanned.
  - Bank Records, 1955-1962; 7 Folders (Box 26, Folder 18-24)
  - Consignment Records, 1956-1987 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Famous Artists School Pay Statements, 1954-1968 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Insurance Records, 1936-1969; 2 Folders (Box 26, Folder 27-28)
  - Loan Agreements, circa 1956-1968 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Loan Agreements, 1976-1987 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Receipts, Art Materials and Framing, 1957-1966 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Receipts, Artwork Given as Gifts to Institutions, 1937-1971 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Receipts, Artwork Sold, circa 1956-1987 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Receipts, 1940-1968; 2 Folders (Box 26, Folder 34-35)
  - Receipts, Dues, 1952-1969 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Receipts, Hardware Supplies and Lumber Company, 1957-1968 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Receipts, Honoraria and other Payments, circa 1951-1980 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Receipts, 1935-1987; 4 Folders (Box 26, Folder 39-42)
  - Receipts, Publication of Artwork, circa 1956-1967 (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - Receipts, circa 1950-1988; 4 Folders (Box 26, Folder 44-47)
  - Receipts, Travel, 1956-1970; 4 Folders (Box 26, Folder 48-51)
    folder 51 not scanned
  - Receipts, Utilities, 1957-1969 (Box 26, Folder 52)
  - Royalty Statements, circa 1955-1964 (Box 26, Folder 53)
  - Royalty Statements, 1965-1988 (Box 26, Folder 54)
  - Savings Account for Peace (Committee for Mark Twain Prayer), 1966-1968 (Box 26, Folder 55)
  - Shahn Personal Business Records, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 56)
  - Survey: Property of Ben Shahn, Roosevelt, NJ, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Tax Records, 1934-1988; 3 Folders (Box 27, Folder 2-4)
  - Court Papers: Shahn and Robert Leslie vs. National Telefilm Associates, Inc., re "The World of Sholom Aleichen,", 1963 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Police Report, Philadelphia Bureau of Police, 1941 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Supreme Court Brief re. the Magazine Eros, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Material from Survey: Property of Ben Shahn, Roosevelt, NJ, 1954 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 27, F1
- Notes and Writings, circa 1933-1988; Series 5; 1.62 Linear feet Boxes 27-28
  This series contains notes and writings by Shahn and others, in addition to lists of artwork, addresses and engagement calendars.
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  5.1: Notes and Writings by Shahn, circa 1933-1986
  5.2: Writings by Others, About Shahn, circa 1950s-1988
  5.3: Writings by Others, Not Shahn-Related, 1935-1966
  - Notes and Writings by Shahn, circa 1933-1986; 5.1
    This series contains addresses, calendars, and lists of artwork, many of which are annotated with prices, in addition to miscellaneous notes written by and to Shahn which include scattered sketches and doodles. The bulk of the series consists of drafts and transcripts of lectures and statements given by Shahn over the course of his career. The writings found here include material used in some of Shahn's most well-known lectures such as those he gave as Charles Eliot Norton Professor of Poetry at Harvard University from 1956-1957 (collected and published by Harvard University Press as The Shape of Content in 1957), on subjects such as artists in colleges, the biography of a painting, nonconformity, and the education of an artist.
    Addresses, calendars, lists and notes are followed by writings arranged in rough chronological order and alphabetically by title thereafter. The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of some addresses and business cards and some miscellaneous notes.
    - Address Book, circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Addresses, Handwritten and Business Cards, circa 1940s-1986 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Engagement Calendar, 1966 January-June (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Engagement Calendar, 1966 July-December (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Fragments, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Lists of Artwork, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Lists of Artwork, circa 1956-1975 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, To and By Shahn, circa 1933-circa 1972 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, To and By Shahn, circa 1940s-circa 1960s; 4 Folders (Box 27, Folder 16-19)
      Partially scanned
      Folder 19 not scanned
    - Notebooks, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 20)
      2 notebooks, 1 in Italian
    - Travel Diary Fragments, London, circa 1950s (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - "A Credo," Woodstock, NY, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - "If I Had to Begin My Art Career Today," at Andover, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - "The Place of the Artist in Modern Society/Some Questions," Smith College, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - "The Question: Who Cares?" University of Wisconsin, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - "Prints,", circa 1950s (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Re: Maccari, circa 1950s (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Re: Museum of Modern Art, circa 1950s (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - "Just What is Realism in Art?" State University of Iowa, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - "Paul Klee," Museum of Modern Art Symposium, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - "Education of an Artist," Jamesine Franklin School of Professional Arts, Inc., 1950 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - "Some Revaluations of Commercial and Fine Arts," Jamesine Franklin School of Professional Arts, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - "American Paintings for the Past Twenty-five Years: An Unorthodox View," Harvard University, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - "Art, as a Positive Value,", 1951 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - "Aspects of Realism," Black Mountain College, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - "Education of a Professional Artist," at Providence, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 36)